# Mona Odeh Machine Learning Engineer

509-333-1486 monazodeh@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/monazodeh twitter.com/monazodeh

Passionate machine learning engineer with 4+ years of experience in predictive modeling and data mining. Excited to implement statistical machine learning solutions for Macro Globe. At Stack Intellect, implemented demand forecasting models improving forecast accuracy by 34%.

### **Experience**

Machine Learning Engineer Stack Intellect Nov 2017 to Jan 2020

## **Key Qualifications & Responsibilities**

- Designed and developed analysis systems to extract information from large scale data.
- Developed customer segmentation algorithm in R leading to 22% increase in market share.
- Optimized personalization algorithms for applications with 2M+ users.
- Applied data mining to shipping consolidation problem, saving \$1.2M.
- Predicted product sales to within 2% by applying logistic regression model.

### **Kev Achievement:**

 Mentored organization on big data and analytics, facilitating receipt of Global IT Innovation Award for customer segmentation algorithm.

### **Machine Learning Engineer**

**Network Corp** 

Aug 2015 to Oct 2017

- Developed molecular dynamics simulations using machine learning algorithms to identify protein-DNA interactions with up to 95% fidelity.
- Interpreted 300+ complex simulation datasets using statistical methods.
- Improved accuracy of simulation by 30% using complex algorithms.
- Developed dimensional data modeling to satisfy OLAP needs.

### Junior SQL Developer

Haste Vital

July 2014 to July 2015

- Updated and optimized 47+ stored procedures using T-SQL.
- Developed PL/SQL stored procedure, functions and style sheets to reduce data retrieval time by 50%.
- Re-structured schemas with 100+ tables to enhance data integrity.

#### Education

# PhD in Machine Learning Carnegie Mellon

2010-2014

- Research paper: Machine Learning, Probabilities Explained published in Journal of Cryptology, June 2017
- Senior data mining project written up in *TechCrunch*.
- Excelled in database and data structure coursework.

# Master of Science in Machine Learning Carnegie Mellon 2008–2010

# Bachelor of Science in Computer Science University of Washington 2004–2008

#### Skills

- Data and Quantitative Analysis
- Decision Analytics
- Predictive Modeling
- Data-Driven Personalization
- Machine Learning Algorithms
- Organizational and analytical skills
- Understanding of technical documentation
- Communication and presentation
- Problem-solving

### **Machine Learning Projects**

- Created social media sentiment analyzer that tracks 150 million posts per day.
- Developed data mining algorithms for 5 clients online.
- See Portfolio at monazodeh.com

# **Machine Learning Papers**

- Machine Learning Practical Futures published in The Computer Journal, January 2018
- AI, Big Data, and the Internet of Things published in TechWallop, June 2019

### **Member, Association for Computing Machinery**

- Connected 50+ new machine learning engineers with experts in the field.
- As a social media director, routinely interacted with 1,200+ members online.